Englishpod.com		Englishpod.com
A: Good evening. My name is Fabio, I'll be your waiter for tonight. May I take your order?		甲:晚上好。我叫法比奥，今晚我将为您服务。我可以为你点菜吗？
B: No, I'm still working on it.		没有，我还在努力。
This menu is not even in English. What's good here?		这份菜单甚至不是英文的。这里有什么好吃的？
A: For you sir, I would recommend spaghetti and meatballs.		先生，我向您推荐意大利面和肉丸。
B: Does it come with coke and fries?		有可乐和薯条吗？
A: It comes with either soup or salad and a complimentary glass of wine, Sir.		它配有汤或沙拉以及一杯免费的葡萄酒，先生。
B: I'll go with the spaghetti and meatballs, salad and the wine.		我要意大利面和肉丸、沙拉和葡萄酒。
A: Excellent choice, your order will be ready soon.		很好的选择，您点的菜很快就好了。
B: How soon is soon?		多久是很快？
A: Twenty minutes?		二十分钟？
B: You know what? I'll just go grab a burger across the street.		你知道吗？我去街对面买个汉堡。街道。