M: Hello English learners and welcome to EnglishPod! My name is Marco.
A: I'm Amira.
M: And Amira and I are here today with a great, great lesson for you.
m:大家好，欢迎来到英语播客！我叫马可。
甲:我叫阿米拉。
m:今天Amira和我在这里给你们上了一堂非常非常好的课。
A: Yes, we are.
M: Today we're gonna be talking about a restaurant.  Amira, why don't you give us a little bit more details?
是的，我们是。m:今天我们来谈谈餐馆。Amira，你为什么不给我们多一点细节？
A: Well, we're talking about a situation in a restaurant and two people are involved – the waiter and the customer. And I don't wanna say anymore.		嗯，我们正在谈论一个餐馆里的情况，涉及到两个人——服务员和顾客。我不想再说了。
M: Okay, don't say anymore, let's just listen to this dialogue and we'll be back later to explain it.		m:好了，不要再说了，我们来听这段对话，一会儿回来解释。
DIALOGUE, FIRST TIME		对话，第一次
A: Oh-oh, what a waiter?  M: What a waiter? He is really angry at this customer and I can't blame him, I would be angry too .		哦-哦，多好的服务员啊！男:多好的服务员啊？他对这位顾客非常生气，我不能责怪他，我也会生气的。
A: Yeah, so, I've seen Marco you have chosen some interesting expressions for us here.  What is the first one?		是的，所以，我看到你为我们选择了一些有趣的表达方式。第一个是什么？
M: Well, the first one is I'm still working on it.		男:嗯，第一个是我还在努力。
A: I'm still working on it.  M: I'm still working on it.		答:我还在努力。M: I还在努力。
A: I'm still working on it.		答:我还在努力。
M: Why don't we listen to some other examples on how you can use this word and then  we'll come back and explain it?		m:我们为什么不听一些关于如何使用这个单词的例子，然后我们再回来解释呢？
A: Did you finish reading the magazine?		你看完这本杂志了吗？
B: I'm still working it。		我还在努力。
C: Did you fix my car?   D: I'm still working on it.		你修好我的车了吗？d:我还在努力。
A: you could say “I'm still working on it” means… M: I still need more time. A: Fantastic. M: Great. Okay, it's clear.		你可以说“我还在努力”意思是……M:I还需要更多的时间。太棒了。男:太好了。好了，安全了。
A: I have another one for you guys, it's a phrase commonly used and you'll hear it all the  time – coke and fries.  M: Coke and fries.  A: Coke and fries. M: Coke and fries. It's a short way of saying “Coca-Cola and French fries".
a:我为你们准备了另一个，这是一个经常使用的短语，你会经常听到——可乐和薯条。m:可乐和薯条。甲:可乐和薯条。m:可乐和薯条。这是“可口可乐和炸薯条”的简称。
A: So, that's basically America's fast food.  M: Yeah. Burger, coke and fries.		所以，这基本上就是美国的快餐了。男:是啊。汉堡，可乐和薯条。
A: Okay. M: Hehe. A: What's next on the menu?   M: On the menu we have a complementary glass of wine.
甲:好的。男:呵呵。甲:菜单上的下一个是什么？m:菜单上我们有一杯附赠的葡萄酒。
A: Complementary glass of wine. M: Complementary glass of wine.
a:一杯葡萄酒。m:一杯葡萄酒。
A: Complementary means…  M: That it's free.  A: Free.  M: Yes.  A: We love that, ha?  M: Yeah, we definitely like free things		答:补充的意思是……男:免费的。答:免费。男:是的。我们喜欢那样，哈？是的，我们当然喜欢免费的东西
A: Well, um, I have another one for us here, another interesting phrase – I'll go with.  M: I'll go with.		嗯，我这里还有一个，另一个有趣的短语——我同意。M: 我会跟去。
A: I'll go with.		甲:我也去。
A: So, basically, it's another way of saying “I'm choosing".   M: Yeah, I'll choose or I'll take.		答:所以，基本上，这是“我在选择”的另一种说法。是的，我会选择或者接受。
A: Okay, very good.  M: Alright, the next word that I wanna take a look at is grab.		好的，非常好。m:好的，我想看的下一个词是grab。
A: Grab. M: Grab.  A: Grab.		答:抢。男:抓。答:抢。
M: Okay, now let's listen to some other examples of how we could use grab in different situations and then we'll come back and explain it.		好的，现在我们来听一些其他的例子，看看如何在不同的情况下使用grab，然后我们再回来解释一下。
A: On your way home can you grab some milk?		在你回家的路上，你能买些牛奶吗？
B: Wait for me please, I need to grab my coat.		请等我一下，我需要拿一下我的外套。
C: Let's grab a cup of coffee.		我们去喝杯咖啡吧。
A: Alright, well, I would understand that go grab means go get quickly.		a:好吧，我明白了，go grab的意思是快速获取。
M: To go get quickly, yeah.  A: Yeah. Alright everyone, so, now it's time to listen one more time to the dialogue and  listen carefully and try to understand why the waiter doesn't like the customer. Let's listen.		去快一点，是的。答:是啊。好了，各位，现在是时候再听一遍对话了，仔细听，试着理解为什么服务员不喜欢这位顾客。让我们听听。
DIALOGUE, SECONDE TIME		对话，第二次
A: Marco, why did this waiter get angry at the customer?		马可，这个服务员为什么对顾客发火？
M: Well, he basically wasted the waiter's time.		男:嗯，他基本上浪费了服务员的时间。
I mean this guy comes into the restaurant,  he is not very polite and he's asking all these questions, in the end he just gets up and says “Uh, I'll just go grab a burger across the street”.		我的意思是，这个人走进餐厅，他不是很礼貌，他问了所有这些问题，最后他只是站起来说，“嗯，我只是去街对面买个汉堡”。
A: Yeah, and I also think that this guy was a lot more casual than the place he was in, right?		是的，我也认为这个人比他在的地方要随意得多，对吗？
M: Yeah, yeah, I think it was a nice, uh, fancy restaurant, so, I think he was in the wrong place.		男:对，对，我认为那是一家很棒的餐厅，所以我认为他来错了地方。
A: so, how many times, Marco, tell me do you really have fast food a week?		那么，多少次，马可，告诉我你真的一周吃快餐吗？
M: Fast food, let's see, uh, Monday, Tuesday, Wednesday… no, I'm just kidding. A: Oh my God. M: No, no, um, I think I get fast food maybe once a week… once or twice a week. Alright, talking about fast food made me hungry, so, I think I'm gonna go grab something to eat myself		快餐，让我想想，嗯，周一，周二，周三…不，我只是开玩笑。哦，我的上帝。男:不，不，嗯，我想我可能一周吃一次快餐……一周一次或两次。好吧，谈论快餐让我饿了，所以，我想我要去抓点东西自己吃
A: Yeah, me too. M: Alright, I hope you guys enjoyed the lesson today and remember that all of this vocabulary is useful for your everyday needs.		是的，我也是。m:好的，我希望你们喜欢今天的课，并记住所有这些词汇对你们的日常需求都是有用的。
A: Yes, well, actually here in EnglishPod we focus on phrases and words that are high frequency and that means that you can use them everyday in your practical life.		是的，实际上在EnglishPod中，我们关注的是高频短语和单词，这意味着你可以在日常生活中使用它们。
M: Exactly, and be sure to go to our website at englishpod.com where you can find many other resources and you can leave your questions and comment at our community forum.		没错，一定要去我们在englishpod.com的网站，在那里你可以找到很多其他资源，你可以在我们的社区论坛留下你的问题和评论。
A: So, thank you very much for listening, we'll be back tomorrow with another great lesson for you, so, until then… Bye!  M: Bye ！		a:非常感谢您的收听，我们明天将为您带来另一堂精彩的课，所以，在那之前…再见！男:再见！