the English part audio review
listen to the meaning then say the vocabulary word
not yet completed, need more time
still working on
suggest
would recommend
free
complimentary
to choose, pick
go with
to get quickly,  grab
let's try that faster
not yet completed, need more time
still working on
to get quickly
grab
suggest
would recommend
to get quickly
grab
to choose, pick
go with
now say the word and hear it in a sentence
still working on
have you decided what to do tonight?
I'm still working on it.
complimentary
would you like a complementary dessert？
go with
I'll go with the red dress instead of the blue one.
grab
let's grab some beers after work.
go with
I'll go with the red dress instead of the blue one.
grab
let's grab some beers after work.