hello everyone welcome to English pod today I'm here with Erica hi Marco
and I'm Marco haha
and we're bringing you a great elementary lesson about a situation at an office that's true today we're gonna learn some phrases for asking for time off
right asking for time off or asking for leave
asking for leave yeah right right
so we're gonna give you some great phrases in vocabulary for when you want to ask for leave
so let's just listen to our dialogue today where at an office where live wants some time off
Mr mckenna do you have a second
I need to talk to you about something
sure live what can I do for you
well I was just wondering you see
I know I've used up all my vacation days this year but my sister's getting married and the wedding is over season well
you want to take some time off is that right
well sir
I was just hoping I might be able to take some unpaid leave this year
what dates are you planning on taking off
I'll need at least 2 months notice so that I can plan for your absence
I was thinking of taking off from September first until the 30
would you be okay with that
well I guess so
well it sounds like the boss wasn't too happy about lives requests
well she wanted to take off for 30 days
so I guess that is a long time
that is a long time I wish I could do that
yeah okay we have some great words for you today so let's start with our language take away
language take away
4 words on our language take away today Erica why don't you tell us the first one
the first word is vacation days
vacation days
vacation days  ---"Vacation days" 指的是员工或学生可以休息、放松或旅行的休假日天数。
so what are vacation days
basically it's the number of personal leave days
so the number of days that you can take to go on vacation mm hmm
how many vacation days do you have
yeah I think I have not so many I only have 10 vacation days
10 vacation well in some countries
there are 10 vacation days is normal
another I guess it's 10 15 even 20 I've heard
yeah yeah well
vacation day
we can't take too many vacation days or else we won't make any more podcast  ---如果我们休假太多，就不能继续做播客了。
I know
why don't we look at our second word overseas
overseas overseas
when you travel overseas you travel over the ocean
over the ocean to another country exactly
okay overseas
okay and our 3rd word for language take away
unpaid leave
so this is time off without pay without pay simple right unpaid leave
and our last word
notice notice
so we have some great examples on how we use notice
and from these examples I'm sure you'll be able to understand exactly what they mean
example one
if you want to quit your job make sure you give enough notice
you'll need to tell us 4 weeks in advance
example two
you didn't give me enough notice about this project  I didn't have enough time to finish it.
so when you give someone notice you give them information in advance in advance right
so if I want to take time off I need to give my boss notice advanced information right 15 day notice or a 20 day notice etc
great so that's our language takeaway for today now we are ready to listen to our dialogue a second time and this time it's gonna be really slow
Mr mckenna do you have a second I need to talk to you about something
sure Liv what can I do for you
well I was just wondering you see
I know I've used up all my vacation days this year but my sister is getting married and the wedding is overseas and well
you want to take some time off is that right
well sir I was just hoping that I might be able to take some unpaid leave this year what dates are you planning on taking off
I'll need at least 2 months notice so that I can plan for your absence
I was thinking of taking off from September first until the 30th
would you be okay with that
I guess so
a lot of non native English speakers sometimes feel quite nervous about asking their boss for time off.
yeah I guess it's a kind of a difficult subject
yeah but today we're gonna teach you some great phrases that you can use next time you need to ask for some time off
great
so why don't we take a look at putting it together
putting it together
okay so I'm putting it together today we're going to talk about some great phrases that you can use when approaching your boss
yes we heard live say this
do you have a second
this is a nice way
to make sure your boss isn't busy when you want to ask him something
right right right
but we could also say this in 2 different ways
let's listen
do you have a minute I want to ask you something
do you have a SEC I need to talk to you
a great way to approach your boss
yeah I love this phrase
do you have a SEC
yeah do you have a SEC it's really natural
okay so you've asked your boss for leave and you want to make sure that he agrees with you yes
and this is how live did it
would you be okay with that
this is a great pattern
and we've got 2 other examples of how you can use it
example one
are you all right with that
example 2
will you be okay with this
example 3
I'm fine with that
okay great examples great patterns
really useful language
yes okay so now let's listen to our dialogue third time
Mr mckenna do you have a second?
I need to talk to you about something.
sure Liv what can I do for you?
well I was just wondering, you see
I know I've used up all my vacation days this year.
but my sister's getting married and the wedding is over season well
you want to take some time off is that right.
well sir
I was just hoping I might be able to take some unpaid
leave this year.
what dates are you planning on taking off?
I'll need at least 2 months notice
so that I can plan for your absence.
I was thinking of taking off from September first
until the 30
would you be okay with that
well I guess so
I really noticed how Liv in this dialogue used a lot of really polite language
hey
yeah I guess when you're talking to your boss
you'd really have to be respectful and you have to use really polite language
what sort of things did she do to make herself seem more polite
well she said a couple of interesting phrases
for example well I was just wondering
yeah I was just wondering
right I was like well
she's kind of setting up to ask for a favor or something yeah
and she also used another phrase that I thought was interesting
yeah she also said I was just hoping that
yes
right
I was just hoping that maybe I could take some time off
yeah again that sort of doesn't sound too strong
so it seems a bit more polite
yeah
because if she said well I want to take some time off
that's too strong yeah
so I was just hoping
and then
well the boss is okay well when do you want to leave and she says well
I was thinking of right I was thinking of
yeah
again if she would have said
I want to yes
too strong right yeah in English
sometimes we are careful to not be too direct
when we're asking for something right
right yeah
because if you're too direct
you sound a little bit impolite
yeah you sound rude
yeah
okay so great tips and great things to take into consideration the next time you're talking into your boss
to take into consideration：
这是一个固定短语，意思是 "考虑"、"把……纳入考虑范围"。
take 是动词，表示 "拿"、"采纳"。
into 是介词，表示 "进入"。
consideration 是名词，意思是 "考虑"、"审慎考虑"。
整句话的意思是：好吧，所以下次和老板交谈时，记得考虑一些很棒的建议和要点。
alright guys
we're out of time but thanks for listening
and be sure to check out our website
englishpod com
right
where you can leave all your questions and comments
and we'll be there to answer them but I guess until then it's goodbye